Stop him!
拦住他!
(RASPING WHISPER) Hunt that man! He must not escape!
去找他！不能让他逃走！
Can we not help them? We can use the Tardis!
我们不能帮助他们吗？我们可以用 TARDIS!
To go to the moon? We'd probably overshoot by a few million years!
到月球去吗？我们可能跑偏一百万年！
Yes, or by a few million miles!
是的, 或者是一百万英里！
I'm afraid the Tardis is not suited to short-range travel.
恐怕 TARDIS 不适合短途
Still, I think we should help them if we can.
我仍然觉得我们应该尽我们所能帮助他们
- Aye.  - Yes.
- 对    - 是
- Still, I think I could get your rocket to the moon.
- You?
- 我仍然觉得我可以把你的火箭弄到月球上去  - 你？
Yes, I have considerable experience in space travel, and so have my two companions.
是的, 在太空旅行方面, 我有相当丰富的经验, 我这两位同伴也是
Doctor, that's splendid! Thank you!
博士, 那太棒了！谢谢你！
- But the rocket is not ready!
- Perhaps you overestimate the difficulty.
- 但火箭条件还不成熟  - 也许你高估了问题了难度
How much more work is required?
需要多少工作量？
It needs fuel and a complete computerised check.
需要燃料, 还需要用电脑进行一次完全的检查
- I can order that.
- No! I would not allow it! The risk is too great!
- 这我可以安排  - 不！我不允许！风险太大了
If there was some other way,
如果有其它的法子
- Believe me, I wouldn't even consider such a risk!
- No!
- 相信我, 我也不会考虑这么高风险的方法  - 不行
(COMPUTER) Commander Radnor
Radnor 指挥官
Radnor. Go ahead.
我是 Radnor, 继续
T-Mat receptions - New York, Moscow, Tokyo -
各 T-Mat 接收站 - 纽约, 莫斯科, 东京
express great concern over continued hold-up.
都对持续停运表达的严正关切
Medical shipments and food awaiting transit to Asiatic centres.
大批医疗用品和食物亟待传输到亚洲中心
Position desperate, Calcutta. Instructions awaited.
fixme
- That's your answer!
- Well, we want to help, as I said!
- 那就是你的答案！  - 我们的确想帮忙, 我说过了
You don't what you're doing! It's suicide!
你不明白你在做什么！这是自杀！
Listen, if this fault lasts much longer,
听着, 如果这个故障继续往下拖着
there's going to be worldwide chaos, and world population is at stake.
就会带来全世界的混乱, 所有地球人都受影响
Infallible T-Mat, putting the world in jeopardy (?)
不倒的 T-Mat, 把全世界推向了危机！
All right, I admit it.
好吧, 我承认
Now this man has to risk his life to get you out of trouble!
现在这个人不得不押上自己的性命来解决你的麻烦
No, not for me, for thousands of people all over the world
不, 不是为我, 是为了全世界成千上万的人
who will die if we don't take this risk!
我们不冒这个险他们就会死
I'm sorry but I've got no alternative.
很抱歉我没有其他方案
- Miss Kelly.  - Sir.
- Kely 小姐  - 头儿
I want all technical personnel working on this.
我要所有的技术人员都来搞这个
I want that rocket prepared for launching!
我要这架火箭可以发射！
Yes, Commander.
是, 指挥官
We'd be grateful for your help.
对于你的帮助, 我们很感激
If that rocket's to reach the moon safely, you'll need more than my help - you'll need a miracle!
要让那个火箭能安全到达月球, 你需要的不只是我的帮助 - 你需要一个奇迹！
(RASPING WHISPER) Continue the search!
继续搜寻!
He must not escape!
不能让他逃走！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
- Commander.
- Yes, Miss Kelly?
- 指挥官  - 什么事, Kelly 小姐？
Do you think it's wise letting these people crew the rocket?
你觉得这样明智吗, 让这些人坐火箭过去
Wise? No, of course it is not wise. But what's the alternative?/?
明智？不, 当然不明智．但没有其它办法了啊
We gave up training astronauts years ago.
我们在多年以前就不再训练宇航员了
- But Who are they?
- Some of Eldred's crazy friends, I imagine,
- 但他们都是什么人？  - Eldred 的一些疯朋友吧, 我猜
- but the man who calls himeself the Doctor said he knows this space travel.
- How can you be sure?
- 但那个自称博士的人说他懂太空旅行  - 你能确信吗？
You weren’t at the briefing, He and the girl know more about space flight than Eldred.
做简报的时候你不在．他和那个女孩儿在太空飞行方面比 Eldred 懂得多
- What about the boy?
- Yes, I'm not sure about him.
- 那那个男孩儿呢  - 是, 我对他不太有把握
(RASPING WHISPER) The emergency link with Earth,
跟地球的紧急连接
- is it ready yet?
- I've nearly finished.
- 好了没有？  - 我快完成了
- Do not make any mistakes!
- I'm not an expert!
- 不要出任何问题！  - 我不是个专家！
- But you will do it?
- Yes!
- 但你能做吗？  - 是的！
Commander, I think I should go as crew on the rocket.
指挥官, 我觉得我应该也到火箭上去
Don't be ridiculous, you're too valuable here!
别傻了, 你在这里太重要了！
How can T-Mat be repaired if I'm not there?
如果我不上去, T-Mat 怎么能修好呢？
- What about one of the technicians who was already over there?
- Osgood's dead.
- 已经在那边的技术人员都不行吗？  - Osgood 已经死了
- Yes, well, what about Fewsham?
- He's incapable of doing it! I think I should go!
- 是, 但是 Fewsham 怎么样？  - 他没有这个能力！我觉得我应该去！
No! You're the only one who really understands T-Mat.
不, 你是唯一真正懂 T-Mat 的人
I can't have you risking your life!
我不能让你拿你的性命去冒险！
But yet you are perfectly prepared to allow them to risk theirs!
但你却允许他们拿性命去冒险！
Don't worry, Miss Kelly we'll be perfectly all right!
别担心, Kelly 小姐, 我们会完全没事的！
But I don't see what good just this emergency link can be.
但我看不出这个紧急连接能有什么用
Even if you had a gigantic army of warriors,
就算你有一只庞大军队, 全都是勇士
you couldn't send them all to conquer Earth.
你也不能把他们都送过去征服地球
(RASPING WHISPER) We do not need an army.
我们不需要一直军队
Earth will be ours for the taking...
地球会是我们的...
(HISSING BREATHING) ..very soon!
...很快就是！
- Doctor...  - Yes?
- 博士...  - 什么事？
Final check on procedure after you land.
最后核对一遍你着陆后的程序
Yes, I know we're to re-establish video link with the Earth.
似的, 我知道我们要重新建立跟地球的视频连接
That's right.
对的
When we can see what's wrong,
一旦我们看出是什么地方出了问题
you can do the rest under Miss Kelly's supervision.
剩下的事你们就可以在 Kelly 小姐的指导下完成了
Right. We're ready when you are.
对．你们准备好了我们就发射了
12...
10...
nine...eight...seven...
9...8...7...
..six...five...four...three...
..6...5...4...3...
..two...one.
..2...1.
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
It's done.
搞定了
- The emergency link will work now.
- Excellent!
- 紧急连接可以工作了  - 非常好！
- What are you going to do?
- Do not ask questions!
- 你打算做什么？  - 不许提问！
Activate the link.
激活连接
- On receive only.
- Receive?
- 设定为仅仅接收  - 接收？
But aren't you going to send...?
但你们不是要传送...？
Activate the link on receive at once!
将连接设置为仅接收, 立刻！
- (KELLY) You've double-checked everything?
- Yes, the fault is definitely on Moonbase.
- 都再三核对过了吧？  - 是的, 故障肯定在月球基地上
Is it possible for you to effect repairs over video?
你有可能通过视频指导完成修复吗？
Provided the fault is not too major.
除非不是什么大故障
- And provided they actually get there with the rocket!
- They'll get there.
- 还得他们乘坐火箭真的能到那儿  - 他们会到那儿的
Why? How do you know? You can't even be sure the rocket's still in one piece!
为什么？你知道知道？你都不能确定那火箭还是不是完整的！
- Miss Kelly!
- What is it, Brent?
- Kelly 小姐！  - 什么事, Brent？
We've got through. The emergency T-Mat link to Moon Control is activating!
我们接通了．与月球控制中心的 T-Mat 紧急连接正在激活！
Is someone coming through?
有谁过来吗？
No, it's on send.
不, 设定在上传模式了
Moonbase must has managed to make a temporary repair.
月球基地肯定是设法临时修复了部分功能
It's all we need. Brent, have a full emergency kit waiting.
这也够了．Brent, 准备好全套紧急救援设备
- I'll join you as soon as possible.
- Yes, Miss Kelly. Standing by.
- 我随后就来   - 好的, Kelly,
Where do you think you are going?
你觉得你是要去哪儿？
If we can send, it's the only thing I can do.
如果我们能发送, 我就只能做这件事情了
You have no idea what conditions are like up there!
你根本不清楚那上面到底什么情况！
I know all too well what are like down here
但我清楚地知道这下面都是什么情况了
Commander, you've stopped me once.
指挥官, 你阻拦了一次
Please don't try it again, otherwise I shall have to go above your head.
请不要再这样了, 否则我就不得不越级了
- She's after your job, Julian!
- Miss Kelly!
- 她要挑战你的位置了, Julian!  - Kelly 小姐!
(TRILLING TONE)
- Thank heavens you've come!
- What happened?
- 感谢上天你来了!  - 什么情况?
Osgood, it must have been space madness./
He just went berserk! Pretty mad. It was terrifying.
Osgood 他肯定是出现了太空症状了, 他直接就发狂了！太疯狂了, 非常吓人
Osgood? But he'd be the last man, I'd have thought!
Osgood？但他应该是最不可能的, 我一直这么以为！
- So did we.
- Where are the others?
- 我们也是  - 其他人在哪儿？
When Osgood fused the controls, Locke tried to stop him.
Osgood 破坏控制系统的时候, Locke 试着阻止他
- Osgood killed him.
- This is fantastic!
- Osgood 杀了他  - 这太不可思议了！
- What about Phipps?
- He was injured too and I put him under sedation.
- Phipps 怎么样了  - 他也受伤了, 我给他用了镇静剂
- And you?
- There's nothing wrong with me.
- 你呢？  - 我没什么事
You look frightened.
你看起来吓坏了
If you'd seen Osgood die, wouldn't you be?
如果你见到 Osgood 死, 你不会吗？
How did he die?
他怎么死的？
His body's outside.
他的尸体在外面
He just went out.
他就那么出去了
Without a pressure suit? I see.
没穿压力服？我明白了
Open all control sections and computer links.
打开所有控制区域和电脑连接
Fewsham, what are you doing?
Fewsham, 你在做什么？
I thought I'd best switch off the emergency link.
我觉得我最好还是把紧急连接关闭
- The trouble we've got could easily burn itself out.
- Sensible.
- 我们目前的问题很可能导致它烧坏  - 有道理
Anyway, it will prevent Commander Radnor sending up another security guard
而且, 这样也能阻止指挥官 Radnor 派一个安全人员上来
to drag me back to Earth!
把我拖回地球去！
(RASPING WHISPER) The other human is still free. Find him!
另外一个人还在逃, 找到他！
He must not interfere with our plans!
不能让他干扰我们的计划！
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
哈罗, 地球控制中心, 这里是月球基地
Emergency! Emergency! How do you read me?
紧急状况！紧急状况！你们能听到吗？
Hello, Earth Control, this is Moonbase.
Emergency! Emergency! Can you hear me?
哈罗, 地球控制中心, 这里是月球基地．紧急状况！紧急状况！你们能听到吗？
(part2 ends)